Personal statement

I'm an enthusiastic and pro-active Web Developer and who makes easy to use websites and applications by discovering how users really think. With 4 years' experience of developing websites and web applications, I have an excellent understanding of how technology can be used to align the requirements of both the business and the customer. I am seeking a new challenge in a progressive and customer-centric organization where I can make the most of my love of technology and my knowledge of user-centered design techniques. My passion for learning - and my involvement in the Web Development - means that I can continually offer the latest technology, practices and ideas to the team, ensuring the company is at the very forefront of customer experiences.

Working in a fast paced environment and producing a high volume of websites. Responsible for developing websites that give users a seamless and rich Internet experience, and for being the first point of contact for end users if they have any queries or technical problems.

Duties:

- optimizing web assets for optimal speed and performance.
- Researching new technologies, software packages and hardware products.
- Advising customers and clients on the limitations of systems and website functionality.
- Make suggestions for improvements in technology, content and user interaction.
- Testing a website before it goes live top identify any problems.
- Designing and deciding on the visual layout of a website.
- Changing the code, software or graphics of existing websites.
- Creating eye-catching and functional digital design concepts across various platforms.

Areas of Expertise

Wordpress(CMS)	HTML	Twitter Bootstrap	Web server configuration
Open cart(CMS)	CSS/CSS3	Website strategy	Jquery/Java
Magneto(CMS)	PHP (Customization)	W3C Validation	Front-end programming
Website Optimization Elementor PRO		Google page speed	HTML To Word press
			Adobe Photoshop

Web Development skills

- Transforming various design projects into reality.
- Able to build consensus and work effectively within a cross-departmental team.
- Experience of Object-Oriented Programming, Continuous Integration, Service-Oriented Architecture and mobile Web development.
- Comprehensive understanding of information architecture principles.
- Productive in both solo and group project environments.

Academic Qualifications

Federal Urdu University Arts Science & Technology - 2009 - 2012 - BS (Computer Science)

Portfolio

Kindly check my portfolio on this url: https://behance.com/farukhkhan_fk

Work Experience:

AUG 2009 - DEC 2011

Front-End Developer

TECTUTIVE- Karachi



SEP 2012 - AUG 2013

Web Developer

WEBFLEET SOLUTIONS - Islamabad

SEP 2014 - JUL 2015

Word press PHP Developer

DNSPAK Pvt Ltd - Islamabad

JAN 2016 - NOVEMBER 2016

Web Developer

Software Base Solutions

MARCH 2017 - PRESENT

Web Developer / Graphics Designer

ALLURESEO - Islamabad

Some Live Projects

https://oz-towing.com/

https://quality1stautorepair.

com/

https://www.nycwheelpros.

com/

http://i-amoving.com/

https://repairs2go.com/

https://modernelectricinc.c

a/

http://nyglazing.com/

https://appliancerepairbroo

klynny.com/

https://wordpress-143823-

1621432.cloudwaysapps.c

om/

https://thepithari.com/

http://a1autobodyshopbroo

klyn.com/

http://tireonenashville.com/

https://epicaircoolingandhe

ating.com/

https://sinarti.com/

https://doorguysnyc.com/

https://rochesterdoorcomp

any.com/

http://furnitureassemblynyc

.com/

http://setupnyc.com/

https://wordpress-188862-

1587479.cloudwaysapps.c

om/

http://plmelectricmaintenan

ce.com/

http://gramercyconstructio

nservices.com/

https://1stchoicegaragedoo

rsrepair.com/

https://atozrenovationsny.c

om/

http://budgetpainters.ca/

Hobbies

Play Cricket, Listen music, Online Gaming etc.

References - Available on request.